<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albert Vill</title>
    <link>https://acvill.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Albert Vill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://acvill.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>🍕🧫 BackgroundI am from New Jersey. New Yorkers may think they have better bagels and pizza, but they’re wrong.
I graduated from Gettysburg College in 2016 with a B.S. in biochemistry and molecular biology. As a first-generation college student, I got my initial exposure to scientific research in the PhagesRock lab under the mentorship of professors Véronique Delesalle and Greg Krukonis.
Currently, I am a PhD candidate in the Brito Lab at Cornell University in the field of Genetics, Genomics &amp;amp; Development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown site personalization</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/posts/hugo_mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/posts/hugo_mods/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;A collection of code snippets and helpful links for building a Hugo site with Blogdown.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restriction enzyme sites across bacterial genomes - implications for metagenomics</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/posts/restenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/posts/restenz/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts on the use of sequence-biased enzymes for metagenomic proximity ligation, and suggestions for best practices.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>
SUBMIT
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 14 August 2021
PDF version
EducationBachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Gettysburg CollegeBiochemistry and Molecular Biology major, 3.70 GPA
Lincoln Scholar – highest merit-based scholarship awarded
Research ExperiencePhD Candidate – Lab of Dr. Ilana Brito, Cornell UniversityDesigning and implementing methods to quantify changes in the composition and function of the human gut microbiome during perturbation and disease - Spring 2017 – present</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects and Resources</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>bracken_plot – a shiny app for taxonomic abundance visualization
Click to expand details…
As a graduate student studying metagenomics, I frequently use Derrick Wood’s Kraken2 software for accurate and lightning-fast classification of short reads. Bracken is complimentary software that uses Kraken reports to produce genus- and species-level abundance estimates. Often, a first step in metagenomic analysis is examining the distribution of different organisms across samples. To that end, I’ve created a simple shiny app for quick, customizable plotting of taxonomic structures encoded in multi-sample Bracken reports.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
