<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albert Vill</title>
    <link>https://acvill.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Albert Vill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://acvill.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown site personalization</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/posts/hugo_mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/posts/hugo_mods/</guid>
      <description>There are many existing blog posts and help pages explaining how to build a Hugo site using blogdown, the best of which is Creating Websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie, Amber Thomas, and Alison Presmanes Hill. But, as when learning anything new, I found myself asking questions about Hugo site formatting and functionality that were not answered by the “how-to” guides. Here, I’ve collected links and code snippets addressing questions about how to toggle features and change the appearance of blogdown site elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restriction enzyme sites across bacterial genomes - implications for metagenomics</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/posts/restenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/posts/restenz/</guid>
      <description>Restriction enzymes (REs) have been the workhorses of molecular biology for decades.1 Primarily considered tools of cloning, REs have found a place in some next-generation sequencing techniques that require efficient production of defined DNA ends for subsequent modification and ligation. For example, most flavors of genome-wide chromosome conformation capture use one or two REs to fragment DNA before dilute ligation of fixed chromatin complexes.2,3 Additionally, chromatin accessibility can be inferred by sequencing RE-digested chromatin4,5, though such methods are less popular than those which utilize sequence-agnostic enzymes like DNase-seq6 and ATAC-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Husband 👫 Scientist 🔬 Phage Phanatic 👾
Currently, I am a PhD candidate in the Brito Lab at Cornell University. My scientific interests include bacterial genomics, host-microbe interactions, and all things bacteriophage.
I’m a regular contributor on Biology Stack Exchange. Come ask a question!
I have two cats 🐈🐈, brothers named Butch Cassidy (black) and the Sundance Kid (tuxedo).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>
SUBMIT
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 19 December 2020
PDF version
EducationBachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Gettysburg CollegeBiochemistry and Molecular Biology major, 3.70 GPA
Lincoln Scholar – highest merit-based scholarship awarded
Research ExperiencePhD Candidate – Lab of Dr. Ilana Brito, Cornell UniversityDesigning and implementing methods to quantify changes in the composition and function of the human gut microbiome during perturbation and disease - Spring 2017 – present</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://acvill.github.io/cv.knit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acvill.github.io/cv.knit/</guid>
      <description>Last updated 19 December 2020
PDF version
 Education Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Gettysburg College Biochemistry and Molecular Biology major, 3.70 GPA
Lincoln Scholar – highest merit-based scholarship awarded
 Research Experience PhD Candidate – Lab of Dr. Ilana Brito, Cornell University Designing and implementing methods to quantify changes in the composition and function of the human gut microbiome during perturbation and disease - Spring 2017 – present</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
